<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ruszkow.ski</title>
    <link>https://ruszkow.ski/</link>
    <description>Recent content on ruszkow.ski</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ruszkow.ski/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Culture Corner: July 2025</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2025-08-01-culture-corner_july-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2025-08-01-culture-corner_july-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;films&#34;&gt;FILMS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All Cheerleaders Die&lt;/strong&gt;: when I asked my friend Alice back in April if I could crash at hers for a night to break up the journey to Cheltenham for 2000 Trees, she &lt;em&gt;immediately&lt;/em&gt; picked the film that we would watch together. I think it says a lot about our friendship that a full &lt;em&gt;three months in advance&lt;/em&gt; she already knew what the mood of the evening should be. This was absolutely terrible; I loved it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Culture Corner: June 2025</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2025-07-01-culture-corner_june-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2025-07-01-culture-corner_june-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;tv&#34;&gt;TV&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taskmaster&lt;/strong&gt;: we were pretty late to the Taskmaster game (and only started it in 2022), ended up absolutely blasting through the first 14 seasons and getting a little tired of it (those COVID seasons really were sub-par). After a bit of a break we&amp;rsquo;re back into season 15 and I am fully a Taskmaster convert once again, I now understand the appeal of Ivo Graham and Jenny Eclair&amp;rsquo;s presence is a lovely reminder of a youth spent listening to Radio 4 comedy (I was a wild child).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Culture Corner: May 2025</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2025-06-01-culture-corner_may-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2025-06-01-culture-corner_may-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;tv&#34;&gt;TV&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Race Across The World&lt;/strong&gt;: as a fussy vegetarian eater and an anxious traveller, I am unlikely to travel especially widely in the world. Race Across The World sounds like it would be my actual nightmare to participate in, but it&amp;rsquo;s an ideal show for me to watch. There&amp;rsquo;s light drama &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; occasionally heart-warming tales &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; you get to see cool and interesting bits of the world.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Silo&lt;/strong&gt;: I read the entire Silo series a few years back, but forgot just how much I enjoyed it until we started watching the series and I was overjoyed to find things actually looking like how I&amp;rsquo;d pictured them. We&amp;rsquo;re not too far into the series yet, but it&amp;rsquo;s fun so far.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Culture Corner: April 2025</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2025-05-01-culture-corner_april-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2025-05-01-culture-corner_april-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;films&#34;&gt;FILMS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Real Pain&lt;/strong&gt;: reminded me how much I miss my Polish grandmother, one of the best people I&amp;rsquo;ve ever known.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;tv&#34;&gt;TV&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You&lt;/strong&gt;: an absolute nonsense show but always entertaining. We&amp;rsquo;re just over half way through, and there is no way I could&amp;rsquo;ve guessed the turns it would take to get here.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;music&#34;&gt;MUSIC&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lonely People With Power by Deafheaven&lt;/strong&gt;: hot damn, blastbeats are so back.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Manning Fireworks by MJ Lenderman&lt;/strong&gt;: I regret missing out on tickets for his Glasgow show, every time I listen to this album I find a new little bit to appreciate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Culture Corner: March 2025</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2025-04-01-culture-corner_march-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2025-04-01-culture-corner_march-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;tv&#34;&gt;TV&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Severance&lt;/strong&gt;: it took the renaming of a group chat and some substantial nagging from friends but yes, we are now fully invested in Severance. It&amp;rsquo;s a little too stressful to completely blast through, but we got through season one at a fair pace. Lots to think about, but mainly how much I want one of the MDR keyboards.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;books&#34;&gt;BOOKS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Last Murder At The End Of The World by Stuart Turton&lt;/strong&gt;:  listening to this, I discovered the limit I have when it comes to the &amp;ldquo;performance&amp;rdquo; element of audiobooks - it&amp;rsquo;s just a touch too theatrical for me. The book itself is OK - some good spots but also a few weird lulls.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Culture Corner: February 2025</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2025-03-01-culture-corner_february-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2025-03-01-culture-corner_february-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;tv&#34;&gt;TV&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grand Designs&lt;/strong&gt;: nothing like being ill for several days to make me yearn for Kevin nodding politely while some bloke insists they won&amp;rsquo;t compromise on their budget, timescale or scope (and then ends up doing so on all three).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fallout&lt;/strong&gt;: I tried to play Fallout 3 a long, long time ago but didn&amp;rsquo;t get far because it got too stressful fast. But now there&amp;rsquo;s a TV show with all the vibes but I can turn away if it&amp;rsquo;s too weird for me? Ideal, really.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Culture Corner: January 2025</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2025-02-01-culture-corner_january-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2025-02-01-culture-corner_january-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I realise I&amp;rsquo;ve basically not been doing anything with this website and that&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a waste. That being said, I&amp;rsquo;m not finding a huge amount of time or motivation to work on personal projects so I need to find something else to fill the space.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The slow death of Twitter dot com has left me with a relative lack of places to express my Thoughts on things I enjoy (or don&amp;rsquo;t), so I think what I might try and do is some kind of monthly dump of my thoughts on stuff. Yeah, you can get some of this from Letterboxd or StoryGraph but this might be more interim thoughts (and I get to say things about music). Okay? Okay. Let&amp;rsquo;s start.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2022 Running Totals</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2022-12-31-2022-running-totals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 16:30:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2022-12-31-2022-running-totals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This year, as in the previous two, I&amp;rsquo;ve been running fairly regularly. I thought it might be interesting to plot my runs across the year. In particular, I had two targets that I&amp;rsquo;d set out at the start of the year:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To run over 100km every month&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To run a half-marathon every month&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I managed to hit the first (despite two bouts of COVID!) but unfortunately missed the second by a single month - I&amp;rsquo;d left my half for June until the last weekend in the month and woke up on the Sunday morning feeling rotten, so only managed a shorter run. 11/12 isn&amp;rsquo;t too bad though!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Basic matplotlib Bar Plot Styling</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2022-11-01-basic-matplotlib-bar-plot-styling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 20:16:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2022-11-01-basic-matplotlib-bar-plot-styling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Last week, my friend&amp;rsquo;s partner was telling me he was starting to look at plotting in Python. Between this and various people at work  getting started with &lt;code&gt;matplotlib&lt;/code&gt;, I thought it might be helpful to do some step-by-step cheatsheets to show how to interact with different chart elements in &lt;code&gt;matplotlib&lt;/code&gt;. Bar plots are one of the most basic (and useful!) plots, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d start there.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In total there are nine different elements covered here, from top-left to bottom right:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Movie Game: An Introduction</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2022-10-18-movie-game_an-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 20:20:10 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2022-10-18-movie-game_an-introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;where-have-you-been-thanks-manchester-orchestra&#34;&gt;Where Have You Been? (thanks Manchester Orchestra)&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had a particularly prolonged busy period of work of&amp;hellip; a year or so? Maybe longer? At this point, honestly who can even understand the passage of time any more. Anyway, that seems to have come to and end for now so I&amp;rsquo;m trying to reclaim my evenings and start actually finishing work on time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As part of that (and with a bit more mental bandwidth to spare after I log off), I&amp;rsquo;m trying to pick up some new projects and get back into the routine of doing some programming for fun rather than just for work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sunshine on Leith</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2022-01-04-sunshine-on-leith/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 21:44:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2022-01-04-sunshine-on-leith/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I recently saw a &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/setalyas/status/1476864080371720197&#34;&gt;very nice tweet&lt;/a&gt; about sunrise and sunset times in London. It looked a lot like a &lt;code&gt;matplotlib&lt;/code&gt; graph, so I decided to look into how it could have been made. A bit of googling took me to an &lt;a href=&#34;https://chrisramsay.co.uk/posts/2017/03/fun-with-the-sun-and-pyephem/&#34;&gt;excellent blog post&lt;/a&gt; about undertaking very similar tasks, from which I learned about &lt;em&gt;different kinds of twilight&lt;/em&gt;. I then realised switching the focus to Edinburgh gave an opportunity for a terrible pun and decided to make my own, so here we are.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album of the Year 2021</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2022-01-01-album-of-the-year-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 15:23:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2022-01-01-album-of-the-year-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every year, top champ &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/philipcopley&#34;&gt;Pip&lt;/a&gt; runs a Facebook group to work out the Album Of The Year within an extended friendship group. For the past few years I&amp;rsquo;ve been making graphs to summarise the results, using some slightly clunky Jupyter notebooks. At first this just analysed the albums chosen by the group, and then last year (after I did my &lt;a href=&#34;https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2020-11-17-dance-dancier-danciest/&#34;&gt;TTNG analysis&lt;/a&gt;) I expanded it to include some Spotify data too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All of the charts for each year can be found on Github &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/asongtoruin/AOTY&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. I find myself gradually tweaking (and hopefully improving!) the code each year, but it&amp;rsquo;s definitely a bit bolted together so I won&amp;rsquo;t bother going into too much detail about it here. There are two graphs I wanted to talk about a bit more, which is why this post exists! I strongly recommend loading each in a new tab and zooming in to have a closer look.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IMDb Series Rating Summaries</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2021-06-27-imdb-series-rating-summaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 19:23:25 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2021-06-27-imdb-series-rating-summaries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in the summary of my &lt;a href=&#34;https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2021-06-23-imdbs-highest-rated-tv-series/&#34;&gt;highest rated TV shows on IMDb&lt;/a&gt; graph, I originally started trying to summarise user ratings for every episode of an individual series. It took a bit more work, but I think I&amp;rsquo;ve got something reasonable now. The layout I decided on ultimately was a scatter plot showing the season averages above a heatmap showing the rating for every episode, highlighting the overall highest and lowest rated episodes too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IMDb&#39;s Highest Rated TV Series</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2021-06-23-imdbs-highest-rated-tv-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 22:36:42 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2021-06-23-imdbs-highest-rated-tv-series/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: this graph works best if you load it in its own tab, zoom in and scroll around. Have fun!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I like to look through posts on &lt;a href=&#34;https://reddit.com/r/dataisbeautiful&#34;&gt;r/dataisbeautiful&lt;/a&gt; for graph inspiration. There can definitely be a lot of noise, but it also has a lot good ideas for data sources and visualisations. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure it was on there that I first saw graphs showing IMDb ratings for different films and TV series, which in turn lead me (inevitably) to &lt;a href=&#34;https://imdbpy.github.io/&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;IMDbPY&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Whenever I&amp;rsquo;m thinking of checking out a different API, there&amp;rsquo;s probably already a Python module for that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mapping England&#39;s Most Common Pub Names</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2021-04-06-mapping-englands-most-common-pub-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 22:10:11 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2021-04-06-mapping-englands-most-common-pub-names/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After making my &lt;a href=&#34;https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2021-03-23-pub-names/&#34;&gt;graphs&lt;/a&gt; about the most common pub names in each country in Great Britain, one thing that really stood out was just how many pubs in England are called &lt;em&gt;Red Lion&lt;/em&gt;. Being from the Midlands that made a lot of sense to me, but a few people who I showed it to seemed quite surprised. That got me thinking about what kind of regional variation there is in pub names. So, why not look at the most popular pub names by county? This gives us a chance to dig into QGIS a bit, which I tend to use a lot at work for producing maps but haven&amp;rsquo;t talked about on here yet. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive in.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pub Names</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2021-03-23-pub-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 19:11:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2021-03-23-pub-names/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A year into lockdown, one of the things I miss the most is going to the pub. Being at home hasn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;stopped&lt;/em&gt; me from drinking beers and talking nonsense at my friends, but it&amp;rsquo;s not quite the same through a screen is it? So, what&amp;rsquo;s my best alternative? Making graphs about pub names. That&amp;rsquo;s definitely it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve separated this out by each country in Great Britain, so here are the graphs for England and Wales, as well as the Scotland one up there in the header.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Actions on a Schedule</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2021-01-21-github-actions-on-a-schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 22:06:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2021-01-21-github-actions-on-a-schedule/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past year or so I&amp;rsquo;ve been using GitHub Actions on a few different&#xA;projects for building documentation and executables. The direct integration into&#xA;GitHub makes it a bit more convenient than Travis, and being able to use&#xA;predefined Actions makes simple processes way easier to set up.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, one thing I hadn&amp;rsquo;t noticed until recently was that you can trigger&#xA;workflows to run &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.github.com/en/actions/reference/events-that-trigger-workflows#scheduled-events&#34;&gt;on a schedule&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;This is an extremely powerful feature that, to me, seems under-publicised. My&#xA;first idea was that gives us the option of setting up auto-updating graphs - so&#xA;I decided to try that out with UK Covid-19 vaccination data. You can see the&#xA;results of this &lt;a href=&#34;https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2021-01-21-covid-19-vaccinations/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;,&#xA;but in this post I&amp;rsquo;m going to run through the (fairly straightforward) set-up I&#xA;used.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Covid-19 Vaccinations</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2021-01-21-covid-19-vaccinations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 21:47:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2021-01-21-covid-19-vaccinations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The UK government has been offering up a lot of open data through its&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://coronavirus.data.gov.uk/&#34;&gt;Coronavirus data portal&lt;/a&gt;, but much of it is&#xA;intense and slightly stressful. One perhaps more positive piece of information&#xA;it offers is the number of vaccinations that have been provided, for both the&#xA;first and second stage. I decided that might be something a bit nicer to plot.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how&#34;&gt;How?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So not only is the government offering up a lot of open data, they&amp;rsquo;ve also&#xA;provided a&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/publichealthengland/coronavirus-dashboard-api-python-sdk&#34;&gt;Python module&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;for easy access to the data, including directly to &lt;code&gt;pandas&lt;/code&gt; dataframes. From&#xA;there it was extremely easy to pull together the data, and there&amp;rsquo;s nothing&#xA;particularly fancy about the graph itself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dance, Dancier, Danciest</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2020-11-17-dance-dancier-danciest/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 21:50:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2020-11-17-dance-dancier-danciest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in the heady days of 2008, Oxford&amp;rsquo;s finest math-rock band TTNG (back then&#xA;still known as This Town Needs Guns) opened their&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/album/2217d2VN6Nn3zzU9mlApdK?si=nfr6tlwHQfKoMAmIfsSrtQ&#34;&gt;self-titled release&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;with a (fantastic) song providing a rather curious declaration -&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/2g14gU0ZxGZ3Te9EjFsT25?si=efWS3BTTQziLPyavvecTcw&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;26 Is Dancier Than 4&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jump forward 12 years to 2020, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been digging around a bit in the Spotify&#xA;API to better understand what data it provides and try to find some fun things&#xA;to plot. In doing so, I spotted (geddit?) that within the object model, every&#xA;track has a series of attributes, one of which is called &lt;em&gt;danceability&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Halloween Heartrate</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-11-03-halloween-heartrate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 22:30:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-11-03-halloween-heartrate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After watching the films I mentioned in my&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-11-03-halloween-timetable/&#34;&gt;Halloween timetable&lt;/a&gt; graph,&#xA;I realised that my watch would have been tracking my heart rate right the way&#xA;through each film, and thought it might be fun to see if my heart rate had been&#xA;particularly affected by any of the films.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On looking at the data, nothing seemed particularly out of the ordinary - except&#xA;one massive spike during Scream. Thinking about it, this also happened to&#xA;correspond to a parcel arriving at the flat - so the buzzer going managed to&#xA;scare me more than any film. Sounds about right.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Halloween Timetable</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-11-03-halloween-timetable/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 21:39:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-11-03-halloween-timetable/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Generally, I&amp;rsquo;m not very into horror films - I&amp;rsquo;m just not that into getting&#xA;scared, and I tend to scare quite easily. Spooky season &lt;strong&gt;is&lt;/strong&gt; spooky season&#xA;though, and when my pal &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/BeardedBakery&#34;&gt;Mike&lt;/a&gt; decided to run&#xA;a vote to pick films for a Halloween movie marathon on our Discord server&#xA;(thanks Mike!), I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but make a timetable for it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how&#34;&gt;How?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hello there &lt;code&gt;matplotlib&lt;/code&gt;, my old friend. As if it would be anything else.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biffy Clyro Chart Positions</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-09-26-biffy-clyro-chart-positions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 16:43:18 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-09-26-biffy-clyro-chart-positions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This graph shows the peak UK chart position reached by each release from&#xA;Scotland&amp;rsquo;s greatest band, Biffy Clyro, to have cracked the top 100. Each point&#xA;is scaled in line with the number of weeks the release has spent in the top 100.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I first came across the idea of a &amp;ldquo;lollipop&amp;rdquo; charts through Spotify&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/spotify/chartify&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;chartify&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; library a while ago, and&#xA;have been trying to think of something that would look good as one. Biffy&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;latest album, &lt;em&gt;A Celebration of Endings&lt;/em&gt;, managed to reach number one in the&#xA;album charts, and that got me thinking about how their previous releases had&#xA;performed in the charts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Download Headliners</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-09-12-download-headliners/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 17:24:49 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-09-12-download-headliners/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first festival I ever went to was Download at Donington Park, in 2005. My&#xA;dad and I returned in 2006 and 2007 - he&amp;rsquo;s been back a few more times since,&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;ve not but it still holds a special place in my heart.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One criticism that gets levelled at the festival is that its headliners tend to&#xA;be taken from a small pool of bands, so I decided to actually graph it. What we&#xA;see is that from around 2011 onwards new main stage headliners become decidedly&#xA;less frequent, with one new headliner &lt;em&gt;at most&lt;/em&gt; appearing in a given year.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Big Five Champions</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-07-30-big-five-champions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 18:36:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-07-30-big-five-champions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update 2021-06-01: updated to include 2020-2021 season, and some visual tweaks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yet another football graph, and yet another bar chart. This one needs to be&#xA;viewed in full-screen to get the full effect!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the (Coronavirus-prolonged) 2019-2020 football season finally draws to a&#xA;close across Europe the traditional &amp;ldquo;big five&amp;rdquo; leagues (England, France,&#xA;Germany, Italy and Spain) seemed to be won by the expected teams, with&#xA;Liverpool&amp;rsquo;s first English title for 30 years proving somewhat of an outlier.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK Bisexual Population</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-07-07-uk-bisexual-population/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 19:07:59 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-07-07-uk-bisexual-population/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some friends of mine run the excellent &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/bihistory/&#34;&gt;Bi History&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;Instagram account that provides useful information and resources about&#xA;bisexuality. I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to think of a way I could produce some nice graphs&#xA;for them, but sadly there seems to be a dearth of good, reliable data sources on&#xA;this topic. There is, however, an ONS survey on &amp;ldquo;Sexual Orientation&amp;rdquo; that&#xA;provides estimates of the UK&amp;rsquo;s LGB population across various classifications.&#xA;The sections offering the most interesting and &amp;ldquo;reliable&amp;rdquo; (ONS&amp;rsquo; definition, not&#xA;mine) populations for bisexuality were the total UK population by year, and the&#xA;population by age group for the latest available year of 2018.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Football League Seasons</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-06-28-football-league-seasons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 18:35:59 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-06-28-football-league-seasons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Generally, I like to complain about my football club. Being a Port Vale fan is&#xA;exhilirating at the best of times but heartbreaking at the worst. There is, at&#xA;time of writing, a slightly hidden presentation on this very site that talks a&#xA;bit about that. See if you can find it (or, ask me and I&amp;rsquo;ll probably just send&#xA;you the link).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A good while ago, I heard the stat that Vale were the team who had spent the&#xA;most seasons in the Football League (as in, the top four tiers of professional&#xA;football in England) without ever playing in the top flight. This was believable&#xA;enough that I&amp;rsquo;ve quoted it a fair few times, but never actually bothered&#xA;checking the data. I realised I should probably actually confirm this, and it&#xA;turns out it was accurate - though it is a title we share with Lincoln City.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Albums to Ruin: database operations</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2020-04-20-albums-to-ruin-database-operations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 10:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2020-04-20-albums-to-ruin-database-operations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This post is a continuation of the development of my &lt;em&gt;Albums to Ruin&lt;/em&gt; Twitter&#xA;bot. This is the first part of actual development of the bot - information&#xA;on the concept and outline can be found in the&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2020-04-14-albums-to-ruin-initial-concept/&#34;&gt;Initial Concept post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to cover the database operations required to power the&#xA;Twitter bot and keep track of what has already been posted and the queue of&#xA;albums to post. This carries on from some of the work done in&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2020-04-17-albums-to-ruin-working-with-the-spotify-api/&#34;&gt;the previous post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Albums to Ruin: working with the Spotify API</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2020-04-17-albums-to-ruin-working-with-the-spotify-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 11:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2020-04-17-albums-to-ruin-working-with-the-spotify-api/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This post is a continuation of the development of my &lt;em&gt;Albums to Ruin&lt;/em&gt; Twitter&#xA;bot. This is the first part of actual development of the bot - information&#xA;on the concept and outline can be found in the&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2020-04-14-albums-to-ruin-initial-concept/&#34;&gt;Initial Concept post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to cover the process required for getting the recently&#xA;played tracks from Spotify and the URL for the album art.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-started&#34;&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First of all, we need to register an application with Spotify. This is done via&#xA;the &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.spotify.com/dashboard/applications&#34;&gt;Developer Dashboard&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;and is relatively straightforward. This provides us with the &lt;code&gt;Client ID&lt;/code&gt; and&#xA;&lt;code&gt;Client Secret&lt;/code&gt; keys that let us access the APIs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Albums to Ruin: Initial Concept</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2020-04-14-albums-to-ruin-initial-concept/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 11:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2020-04-14-albums-to-ruin-initial-concept/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;inspiration&#34;&gt;Inspiration&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve seen a few posts shared around from the Instagram account&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/colorpalette.cinema/&#34;&gt;colorpalette.cinema&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of a nice colour palette (indeed, a few years ago I had a&#xA;Twitter bot running that did something similar with&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitter.com/marvelcovers&#34;&gt;Marvel comics covers&lt;/a&gt;) and it got me&#xA;thinking about whether I could do something similar of my own.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-idea-and-an-initial-outline&#34;&gt;The idea, and an initial outline&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As you might have guessed from the post title, my plan is to make something&#xA;similar for album covers. I&amp;rsquo;m a big music dork and pleasing covers are part of&#xA;the reason why I still buy records, so this is a natural fit for me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2019 Gigs</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-01-28-2019-gigs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 22:24:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-01-28-2019-gigs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A calendar plot showing every gig I went to last year, including festivals.&#xA;Every orange square represents a day where I saw live music, in effect.&#xA;Mid-September to mid-December was a bit of a wild time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how&#34;&gt;How?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The two steps needed to produce this are almost entirely separate:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Getting and processing the data&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Producing the graph&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-the-data&#34;&gt;Getting the data&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Google allows you to download an ICS file of all of your calendar events via its&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://calendar.google.com/calendar/r/settings/export&#34;&gt;export&lt;/a&gt; functionality.&#xA;This, however, contains &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; events from your calendar, so it needs a bit of&#xA;work. I wrote a short script to extract all of the 2019 events, and then&#xA;manually deleted rows that didn&amp;rsquo;t relate to gigs. Is it elegant? No, but the&#xA;majority of events in my calendar are indeed gigs, so it wasn&amp;rsquo;t too much effort.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>English Football&#39;s Top Goalscorers</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2019-10-29-english-footballs-top-goalscorers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 23:13:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2019-10-29-english-footballs-top-goalscorers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The top 8 all-time goalscorers in English football. Why 8? Well, I wanted to do&#xA;the top 10 but couldn&amp;rsquo;t get &lt;code&gt;PyWaffle&lt;/code&gt; to play well with &lt;code&gt;subplots&lt;/code&gt; and 10 or&#xA;more figures. Plus, nobody wants to see 9 figures, so 8 it is.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how&#34;&gt;How?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rdquo; section kind of gave this away, but it comes through using &lt;code&gt;subplots&lt;/code&gt;&#xA;in &lt;code&gt;PyWaffle&lt;/code&gt;, as suggested by the docs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The main issue with this was trying to use the flat version of the font for the&#xA;individual waffle titles and the 3D font for the main header. The issue is that&#xA;when installed, the font shows as two separate &amp;ldquo;faces&amp;rdquo; in Windows. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t&#xA;work out how to get &lt;code&gt;matplotlib&lt;/code&gt; to distinguish between the two, so as a&#xA;workaround I just linked directly to the fonts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Travis &#43; PyInstaller &#43; GitHub Releases</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2019-10-21-travis-&#43;-pyinstaller-&#43;-github-releases/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2019-10-21-travis-&#43;-pyinstaller-&#43;-github-releases/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Part of one of the projects I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on in my day job recently has&#xA;involved taking over the development of a tool that implements some simple data&#xA;anonymisation. This includes the deployment of an executable that can be used by&#xA;non-technical staff, who will likely be the main users of the tool. It&amp;rsquo;s also&#xA;highly likely that all of those staff will be working on Windows PCs. As the&#xA;executable is created through PyInstaller, this means the executable needs to&#xA;be built in a Windows environment. Initially, I&amp;rsquo;d just been doing this locally&#xA;on my PC to create the executable for distribution.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Edinburgh 2017 Temperatures</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2019-10-10-edinburgh-2017-temperatures/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 23:15:26 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2019-10-10-edinburgh-2017-temperatures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A ridge plot (i.e. overlapping distributions) showing the average hourly&#xA;temperatures at a particular location in Edinburgh in 2017, for the roughly&#xA;daytime hours of 7am-7pm.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how&#34;&gt;How?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is based quite heavily on&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://seaborn.pydata.org/examples/kde_ridgeplot.html&#34;&gt;an example&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;given as part of the &lt;code&gt;seaborn&lt;/code&gt; documentation. The only real tweaks made to This&#xA;are to use the average temperature to determine the hue rather than just the row&#xA;and some neat labelling.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This site has long-term data available so ideally I&amp;rsquo;d like to create an&#xA;animation showing the changes in temperature over time, though that seems like&#xA;an optimistic goal at the moment!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NFL Injury Data</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2019-10-07-nfl-injury-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 21:47:04 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2019-10-07-nfl-injury-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update 2021-04-30: Graphs updated with 2020 data, and a nicer font (Bariol, from Atipo Foundry)&lt;/em&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Update 2020-02-16: Graphs updated with 2019 data&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The NFL puts out injury data each year, covering three areas. The cover image&#xA;for this post provides the headline stat of concussions, but information is also&#xA;provided for ACL Tears:&#xA;&#xA;  &lt;div class=&#34;img-outer&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;https://ruszkow.ski/img/graphs/nfl-injuries/acl-tears.png&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;img class=&#34;scaled-img&#34; src=&#34;https://ruszkow.ski/img/graphs/nfl-injuries/acl-tears.png&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;and MCL Tears:&#xA;&#xA;  &lt;div class=&#34;img-outer&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;https://ruszkow.ski/img/graphs/nfl-injuries/mcl-tears.png&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;img class=&#34;scaled-img&#34; src=&#34;https://ruszkow.ski/img/graphs/nfl-injuries/mcl-tears.png&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how&#34;&gt;How?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A stacked bar chart in &lt;code&gt;matplotlib&lt;/code&gt;, with a bit of post-processing to make the&#xA;graphs look nice. Honestly, the biggest hassle involved in making these graphs&#xA;was getting the data itself, as the NFL inexplicably only seems to embed the&#xA;values as images.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Astronauts</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2019-09-16-astronauts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 23:13:29 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2019-09-16-astronauts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update 2019-10-22: PyWaffle version updated to allow use of &lt;code&gt;vertical&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A waffle chart showing the number of astronauts to have achieved distance&#xA;milestones in space.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Space is cool, humans travelling in space is extra cool and this gives an&#xA;interesting way to see that a perhaps surprisingly large number of humans have&#xA;travelled to space, though very few have actually set foot on the moon.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was somewhat difficult to find precise details about this - hence the&#xA;slightly old date associated with the values. This is my best interpretation of&#xA;what&amp;rsquo;s on Wikipedia.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Initial Set-Up of PiHole</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/pihole-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/pihole-setup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;pihole-set-up&#34;&gt;PiHole Set-Up&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;equipment&#34;&gt;Equipment&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Already had most of the things required, needed:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Micro-USB to Ethernet cable&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;microSD card&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Short Ethernet cable&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;setting-up-the-raspberry-pi&#34;&gt;Setting up the Raspberry Pi&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Download Raspbian Lite image (for the time being, we only want to use&#xA;this for PiHole)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Flash onto microSD with Etcher&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Plug everything in&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cock-up 1: Raspbian now disables SSH by default. Need to plug in a screen&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Change the default password on activating SSH (we&amp;rsquo;ll fix this later but&#xA;it&amp;rsquo;s still good to get this done early)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Shutdown, unplug screen etc, set up cables as actually desired and re-plug in&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;SSH in!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Run updates (&lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get update&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get upgrade&lt;/code&gt;), reboot&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Set up SSH&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;$ cd ~&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;$ mkdir .ssh&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;$ cd .ssh&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;$ nano authorized_keys&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Use PuTTYgen to generate keys&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cock-up 2: PuTTYgen&amp;rsquo;s default public key is in an incompatible format.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Delete first two rows and last row&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add &lt;code&gt;ssh-rsa &lt;/code&gt; before the key&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Delete all carriage returns&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Reboot to check it works&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Remove password authentication&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;installing-pihole&#34;&gt;Installing PiHole&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;curl -sSL https://install.pi-hole.net | bash&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Change from the default web admin password with &lt;code&gt;pihole -a -p&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;hello&#34;&gt;Hello!&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m Adam. By day a transport planner, by night a self-taught amateur programmer.&#xA;In both situations I try and use Python as much as possible, though once I&amp;rsquo;ve&#xA;got a few projects out of the way (such as this site) I&amp;rsquo;m planning on&#xA;learning R.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This site is intended mostly as a place to detail the various projects I end up&#xA;working on for the handful of people who ask me how they&amp;rsquo;re done. It&amp;rsquo;s probably&#xA;not going to be super interesting or updated with any well-defined regularity,&#xA;but hopefully there might be something someone out there finds informative.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
