<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Graphs on ruszkow.ski</title>
    <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Graphs on ruszkow.ski</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 21:44:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sunshine on Leith</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2022-01-04-sunshine-on-leith/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 21:44:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2022-01-04-sunshine-on-leith/</guid>
      <description>What? I recently saw a very nice tweet about sunrise and sunset times in London. It looked a lot like a matplotlib graph, so I decided to look into how it could have been made. A bit of googling took me to an excellent blog post about undertaking very similar tasks, from which I learned about different kinds of twilight. I then realised switching the focus to Edinburgh gave an opportunity for a terrible pun and decided to make my own, so here we are.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IMDb Series Rating Summaries</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2021-06-27-imdb-series-rating-summaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 19:23:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2021-06-27-imdb-series-rating-summaries/</guid>
      <description>What? As I mentioned in the summary of my highest rated TV shows on IMDb graph, I originally started trying to summarise user ratings for every episode of an individual series. It took a bit more work, but I think I&amp;rsquo;ve got something reasonable now. The layout I decided on ultimately was a scatter plot showing the season averages above a heatmap showing the rating for every episode, highlighting the overall highest and lowest rated episodes too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IMDb&#39;s Highest Rated TV Series</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2021-06-23-imdbs-highest-rated-tv-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 22:36:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2021-06-23-imdbs-highest-rated-tv-series/</guid>
      <description>Note: this graph works best if you load it in its own tab, zoom in and scroll around. Have fun!
What? Sometimes I like to look through posts on r/dataisbeautiful for graph inspiration. There can definitely be a lot of noise, but it also has a lot good ideas for data sources and visualisations. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure it was on there that I first saw graphs showing IMDb ratings for different films and TV series, which in turn lead me (inevitably) to IMDbPY.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pub Names</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2021-03-23-pub-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 19:11:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2021-03-23-pub-names/</guid>
      <description>What? A year into lockdown, one of the things I miss the most is going to the pub. Being at home hasn&amp;rsquo;t stopped me from drinking beers and talking nonsense at my friends, but it&amp;rsquo;s not quite the same through a screen is it? So, what&amp;rsquo;s my best alternative? Making graphs about pub names. That&amp;rsquo;s definitely it.
I&amp;rsquo;ve separated this out by each country in Great Britain, so here are the graphs for England and Wales, as well as the Scotland one up there in the header.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Covid-19 Vaccinations</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2021-01-21-covid-19-vaccinations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 21:47:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2021-01-21-covid-19-vaccinations/</guid>
      <description>What? The UK government has been offering up a lot of open data through its Coronavirus data portal, but much of it is intense and slightly stressful. One perhaps more positive piece of information it offers is the number of vaccinations that have been provided, for both the first and second stage. I decided that might be something a bit nicer to plot.
How? So not only is the government offering up a lot of open data, they&amp;rsquo;ve also provided a Python module for easy access to the data, including directly to pandas dataframes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Halloween Heartrate</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-11-03-halloween-heartrate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 22:30:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-11-03-halloween-heartrate/</guid>
      <description>What? After watching the films I mentioned in my Halloween timetable graph, I realised that my watch would have been tracking my heart rate right the way through each film, and thought it might be fun to see if my heart rate had been particularly affected by any of the films.
On looking at the data, nothing seemed particularly out of the ordinary - except one massive spike during Scream. Thinking about it, this also happened to correspond to a parcel arriving at the flat - so the buzzer going managed to scare me more than any film.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Halloween Timetable</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-11-03-halloween-timetable/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 21:39:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-11-03-halloween-timetable/</guid>
      <description>What? Generally, I&amp;rsquo;m not very into horror films - I&amp;rsquo;m just not that into getting scared, and I tend to scare quite easily. Spooky season is spooky season though, and when my pal Mike decided to run a vote to pick films for a Halloween movie marathon on our Discord server (thanks Mike!), I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but make a timetable for it.
How? Hello there matplotlib, my old friend. As if it would be anything else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biffy Clyro Chart Positions</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-09-26-biffy-clyro-chart-positions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 16:43:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-09-26-biffy-clyro-chart-positions/</guid>
      <description>What? This graph shows the peak UK chart position reached by each release from Scotland&amp;rsquo;s greatest band, Biffy Clyro, to have cracked the top 100. Each point is scaled in line with the number of weeks the release has spent in the top 100.
I first came across the idea of a &amp;ldquo;lollipop&amp;rdquo; charts through Spotify&amp;rsquo;s chartify library a while ago, and have been trying to think of something that would look good as one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Download Headliners</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-09-12-download-headliners/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 17:24:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-09-12-download-headliners/</guid>
      <description>What? The first festival I ever went to was Download at Donington Park, in 2005. My dad and I returned in 2006 and 2007 - he&amp;rsquo;s been back a few more times since, I&amp;rsquo;ve not but it still holds a special place in my heart.
One criticism that gets levelled at the festival is that its headliners tend to be taken from a small pool of bands, so I decided to actually graph it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Five Champions</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-07-30-big-five-champions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 18:36:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-07-30-big-five-champions/</guid>
      <description>Update 2021-06-01: updated to include 2020-2021 season, and some visual tweaks
What? Yet another football graph, and yet another bar chart. This one needs to be viewed in full-screen to get the full effect!
As the (Coronavirus-prolonged) 2019-2020 football season finally draws to a close across Europe the traditional &amp;ldquo;big five&amp;rdquo; leagues (England, France, Germany, Italy and Spain) seemed to be won by the expected teams, with Liverpool&amp;rsquo;s first English title for 30 years proving somewhat of an outlier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UK Bisexual Population</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-07-07-uk-bisexual-population/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 19:07:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-07-07-uk-bisexual-population/</guid>
      <description>What? Some friends of mine run the excellent Bi History Instagram account that provides useful information and resources about bisexuality. I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to think of a way I could produce some nice graphs for them, but sadly there seems to be a dearth of good, reliable data sources on this topic. There is, however, an ONS survey on &amp;ldquo;Sexual Orientation&amp;rdquo; that provides estimates of the UK&amp;rsquo;s LGB population across various classifications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Football League Seasons</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-06-28-football-league-seasons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 18:35:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-06-28-football-league-seasons/</guid>
      <description>What? Generally, I like to complain about my football club. Being a Port Vale fan is exhilirating at the best of times but heartbreaking at the worst. There is, at time of writing, a slightly hidden presentation on this very site that talks a bit about that. See if you can find it (or, ask me and I&amp;rsquo;ll probably just send you the link).
A good while ago, I heard the stat that Vale were the team who had spent the most seasons in the Football League (as in, the top four tiers of professional football in England) without ever playing in the top flight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019 Gigs</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-01-28-2019-gigs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 22:24:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-01-28-2019-gigs/</guid>
      <description>What? A calendar plot showing every gig I went to last year, including festivals. Every orange square represents a day where I saw live music, in effect. Mid-September to mid-December was a bit of a wild time.
How? The two steps needed to produce this are almost entirely separate:
 Getting and processing the data Producing the graph  Getting the data Google allows you to download an ICS file of all of your calendar events via its export functionality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>English Football&#39;s Top Goalscorers</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2019-10-29-english-footballs-top-goalscorers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 23:13:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2019-10-29-english-footballs-top-goalscorers/</guid>
      <description>What? The top 8 all-time goalscorers in English football. Why 8? Well, I wanted to do the top 10 but couldn&amp;rsquo;t get PyWaffle to play well with subplots and 10 or more figures. Plus, nobody wants to see 9 figures, so 8 it is.
How? The &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rdquo; section kind of gave this away, but it comes through using subplots in PyWaffle, as suggested by the docs.
The main issue with this was trying to use the flat version of the font for the individual waffle titles and the 3D font for the main header.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edinburgh 2017 Temperatures</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2019-10-10-edinburgh-2017-temperatures/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 23:15:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2019-10-10-edinburgh-2017-temperatures/</guid>
      <description>What? A ridge plot (i.e. overlapping distributions) showing the average hourly temperatures at a particular location in Edinburgh in 2017, for the roughly daytime hours of 7am-7pm.
How? This is based quite heavily on an example given as part of the seaborn documentation. The only real tweaks made to This are to use the average temperature to determine the hue rather than just the row and some neat labelling.
This site has long-term data available so ideally I&amp;rsquo;d like to create an animation showing the changes in temperature over time, though that seems like an optimistic goal at the moment!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NFL Injury Data</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2019-10-07-nfl-injury-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 21:47:04 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2019-10-07-nfl-injury-data/</guid>
      <description>Update 2021-04-30: Graphs updated with 2020 data, and a nicer font (Bariol, from Atipo Foundry) Update 2020-02-16: Graphs updated with 2019 data
What? The NFL puts out injury data each year, covering three areas. The cover image for this post provides the headline stat of concussions, but information is also provided for ACL Tears:   and MCL Tears:   How? A stacked bar chart in matplotlib, with a bit of post-processing to make the graphs look nice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Astronauts</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2019-09-16-astronauts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 23:13:29 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2019-09-16-astronauts/</guid>
      <description>Update 2019-10-22: PyWaffle version updated to allow use of vertical
What? A waffle chart showing the number of astronauts to have achieved distance milestones in space.
Space is cool, humans travelling in space is extra cool and this gives an interesting way to see that a perhaps surprisingly large number of humans have travelled to space, though very few have actually set foot on the moon.
It was somewhat difficult to find precise details about this - hence the slightly old date associated with the values.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
