<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Graphs on ruszkow.ski</title>
    <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Graphs on ruszkow.ski</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 16:30:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2022 Running Totals</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2022-12-31-2022-running-totals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 16:30:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2022-12-31-2022-running-totals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This year, as in the previous two, I&amp;rsquo;ve been running fairly regularly. I thought it might be interesting to plot my runs across the year. In particular, I had two targets that I&amp;rsquo;d set out at the start of the year:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To run over 100km every month&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To run a half-marathon every month&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I managed to hit the first (despite two bouts of COVID!) but unfortunately missed the second by a single month - I&amp;rsquo;d left my half for June until the last weekend in the month and woke up on the Sunday morning feeling rotten, so only managed a shorter run. 11/12 isn&amp;rsquo;t too bad though!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Basic matplotlib Bar Plot Styling</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2022-11-01-basic-matplotlib-bar-plot-styling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 20:16:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2022-11-01-basic-matplotlib-bar-plot-styling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Last week, my friend&amp;rsquo;s partner was telling me he was starting to look at plotting in Python. Between this and various people at work  getting started with &lt;code&gt;matplotlib&lt;/code&gt;, I thought it might be helpful to do some step-by-step cheatsheets to show how to interact with different chart elements in &lt;code&gt;matplotlib&lt;/code&gt;. Bar plots are one of the most basic (and useful!) plots, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d start there.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In total there are nine different elements covered here, from top-left to bottom right:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sunshine on Leith</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2022-01-04-sunshine-on-leith/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 21:44:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2022-01-04-sunshine-on-leith/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I recently saw a &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/setalyas/status/1476864080371720197&#34;&gt;very nice tweet&lt;/a&gt; about sunrise and sunset times in London. It looked a lot like a &lt;code&gt;matplotlib&lt;/code&gt; graph, so I decided to look into how it could have been made. A bit of googling took me to an &lt;a href=&#34;https://chrisramsay.co.uk/posts/2017/03/fun-with-the-sun-and-pyephem/&#34;&gt;excellent blog post&lt;/a&gt; about undertaking very similar tasks, from which I learned about &lt;em&gt;different kinds of twilight&lt;/em&gt;. I then realised switching the focus to Edinburgh gave an opportunity for a terrible pun and decided to make my own, so here we are.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IMDb Series Rating Summaries</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2021-06-27-imdb-series-rating-summaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 19:23:25 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2021-06-27-imdb-series-rating-summaries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in the summary of my &lt;a href=&#34;https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2021-06-23-imdbs-highest-rated-tv-series/&#34;&gt;highest rated TV shows on IMDb&lt;/a&gt; graph, I originally started trying to summarise user ratings for every episode of an individual series. It took a bit more work, but I think I&amp;rsquo;ve got something reasonable now. The layout I decided on ultimately was a scatter plot showing the season averages above a heatmap showing the rating for every episode, highlighting the overall highest and lowest rated episodes too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IMDb&#39;s Highest Rated TV Series</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2021-06-23-imdbs-highest-rated-tv-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 22:36:42 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2021-06-23-imdbs-highest-rated-tv-series/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: this graph works best if you load it in its own tab, zoom in and scroll around. Have fun!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I like to look through posts on &lt;a href=&#34;https://reddit.com/r/dataisbeautiful&#34;&gt;r/dataisbeautiful&lt;/a&gt; for graph inspiration. There can definitely be a lot of noise, but it also has a lot good ideas for data sources and visualisations. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure it was on there that I first saw graphs showing IMDb ratings for different films and TV series, which in turn lead me (inevitably) to &lt;a href=&#34;https://imdbpy.github.io/&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;IMDbPY&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Whenever I&amp;rsquo;m thinking of checking out a different API, there&amp;rsquo;s probably already a Python module for that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pub Names</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2021-03-23-pub-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 19:11:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2021-03-23-pub-names/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A year into lockdown, one of the things I miss the most is going to the pub. Being at home hasn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;stopped&lt;/em&gt; me from drinking beers and talking nonsense at my friends, but it&amp;rsquo;s not quite the same through a screen is it? So, what&amp;rsquo;s my best alternative? Making graphs about pub names. That&amp;rsquo;s definitely it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve separated this out by each country in Great Britain, so here are the graphs for England and Wales, as well as the Scotland one up there in the header.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Covid-19 Vaccinations</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2021-01-21-covid-19-vaccinations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 21:47:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2021-01-21-covid-19-vaccinations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The UK government has been offering up a lot of open data through its&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://coronavirus.data.gov.uk/&#34;&gt;Coronavirus data portal&lt;/a&gt;, but much of it is&#xA;intense and slightly stressful. One perhaps more positive piece of information&#xA;it offers is the number of vaccinations that have been provided, for both the&#xA;first and second stage. I decided that might be something a bit nicer to plot.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how&#34;&gt;How?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So not only is the government offering up a lot of open data, they&amp;rsquo;ve also&#xA;provided a&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/publichealthengland/coronavirus-dashboard-api-python-sdk&#34;&gt;Python module&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;for easy access to the data, including directly to &lt;code&gt;pandas&lt;/code&gt; dataframes. From&#xA;there it was extremely easy to pull together the data, and there&amp;rsquo;s nothing&#xA;particularly fancy about the graph itself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Halloween Heartrate</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-11-03-halloween-heartrate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 22:30:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-11-03-halloween-heartrate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After watching the films I mentioned in my&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-11-03-halloween-timetable/&#34;&gt;Halloween timetable&lt;/a&gt; graph,&#xA;I realised that my watch would have been tracking my heart rate right the way&#xA;through each film, and thought it might be fun to see if my heart rate had been&#xA;particularly affected by any of the films.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On looking at the data, nothing seemed particularly out of the ordinary - except&#xA;one massive spike during Scream. Thinking about it, this also happened to&#xA;correspond to a parcel arriving at the flat - so the buzzer going managed to&#xA;scare me more than any film. Sounds about right.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Halloween Timetable</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-11-03-halloween-timetable/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 21:39:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-11-03-halloween-timetable/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Generally, I&amp;rsquo;m not very into horror films - I&amp;rsquo;m just not that into getting&#xA;scared, and I tend to scare quite easily. Spooky season &lt;strong&gt;is&lt;/strong&gt; spooky season&#xA;though, and when my pal &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/BeardedBakery&#34;&gt;Mike&lt;/a&gt; decided to run&#xA;a vote to pick films for a Halloween movie marathon on our Discord server&#xA;(thanks Mike!), I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but make a timetable for it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how&#34;&gt;How?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hello there &lt;code&gt;matplotlib&lt;/code&gt;, my old friend. As if it would be anything else.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biffy Clyro Chart Positions</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-09-26-biffy-clyro-chart-positions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 16:43:18 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-09-26-biffy-clyro-chart-positions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This graph shows the peak UK chart position reached by each release from&#xA;Scotland&amp;rsquo;s greatest band, Biffy Clyro, to have cracked the top 100. Each point&#xA;is scaled in line with the number of weeks the release has spent in the top 100.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I first came across the idea of a &amp;ldquo;lollipop&amp;rdquo; charts through Spotify&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/spotify/chartify&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;chartify&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; library a while ago, and&#xA;have been trying to think of something that would look good as one. Biffy&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;latest album, &lt;em&gt;A Celebration of Endings&lt;/em&gt;, managed to reach number one in the&#xA;album charts, and that got me thinking about how their previous releases had&#xA;performed in the charts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Download Headliners</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-09-12-download-headliners/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 17:24:49 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-09-12-download-headliners/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first festival I ever went to was Download at Donington Park, in 2005. My&#xA;dad and I returned in 2006 and 2007 - he&amp;rsquo;s been back a few more times since,&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;ve not but it still holds a special place in my heart.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One criticism that gets levelled at the festival is that its headliners tend to&#xA;be taken from a small pool of bands, so I decided to actually graph it. What we&#xA;see is that from around 2011 onwards new main stage headliners become decidedly&#xA;less frequent, with one new headliner &lt;em&gt;at most&lt;/em&gt; appearing in a given year.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Big Five Champions</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-07-30-big-five-champions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 18:36:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-07-30-big-five-champions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update 2021-06-01: updated to include 2020-2021 season, and some visual tweaks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yet another football graph, and yet another bar chart. This one needs to be&#xA;viewed in full-screen to get the full effect!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the (Coronavirus-prolonged) 2019-2020 football season finally draws to a&#xA;close across Europe the traditional &amp;ldquo;big five&amp;rdquo; leagues (England, France,&#xA;Germany, Italy and Spain) seemed to be won by the expected teams, with&#xA;Liverpool&amp;rsquo;s first English title for 30 years proving somewhat of an outlier.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK Bisexual Population</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-07-07-uk-bisexual-population/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 19:07:59 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-07-07-uk-bisexual-population/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some friends of mine run the excellent &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/bihistory/&#34;&gt;Bi History&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;Instagram account that provides useful information and resources about&#xA;bisexuality. I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to think of a way I could produce some nice graphs&#xA;for them, but sadly there seems to be a dearth of good, reliable data sources on&#xA;this topic. There is, however, an ONS survey on &amp;ldquo;Sexual Orientation&amp;rdquo; that&#xA;provides estimates of the UK&amp;rsquo;s LGB population across various classifications.&#xA;The sections offering the most interesting and &amp;ldquo;reliable&amp;rdquo; (ONS&amp;rsquo; definition, not&#xA;mine) populations for bisexuality were the total UK population by year, and the&#xA;population by age group for the latest available year of 2018.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Football League Seasons</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-06-28-football-league-seasons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 18:35:59 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-06-28-football-league-seasons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Generally, I like to complain about my football club. Being a Port Vale fan is&#xA;exhilirating at the best of times but heartbreaking at the worst. There is, at&#xA;time of writing, a slightly hidden presentation on this very site that talks a&#xA;bit about that. See if you can find it (or, ask me and I&amp;rsquo;ll probably just send&#xA;you the link).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A good while ago, I heard the stat that Vale were the team who had spent the&#xA;most seasons in the Football League (as in, the top four tiers of professional&#xA;football in England) without ever playing in the top flight. This was believable&#xA;enough that I&amp;rsquo;ve quoted it a fair few times, but never actually bothered&#xA;checking the data. I realised I should probably actually confirm this, and it&#xA;turns out it was accurate - though it is a title we share with Lincoln City.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2019 Gigs</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-01-28-2019-gigs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 22:24:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2020-01-28-2019-gigs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A calendar plot showing every gig I went to last year, including festivals.&#xA;Every orange square represents a day where I saw live music, in effect.&#xA;Mid-September to mid-December was a bit of a wild time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how&#34;&gt;How?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The two steps needed to produce this are almost entirely separate:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Getting and processing the data&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Producing the graph&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-the-data&#34;&gt;Getting the data&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Google allows you to download an ICS file of all of your calendar events via its&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://calendar.google.com/calendar/r/settings/export&#34;&gt;export&lt;/a&gt; functionality.&#xA;This, however, contains &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; events from your calendar, so it needs a bit of&#xA;work. I wrote a short script to extract all of the 2019 events, and then&#xA;manually deleted rows that didn&amp;rsquo;t relate to gigs. Is it elegant? No, but the&#xA;majority of events in my calendar are indeed gigs, so it wasn&amp;rsquo;t too much effort.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>English Football&#39;s Top Goalscorers</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2019-10-29-english-footballs-top-goalscorers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 23:13:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2019-10-29-english-footballs-top-goalscorers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The top 8 all-time goalscorers in English football. Why 8? Well, I wanted to do&#xA;the top 10 but couldn&amp;rsquo;t get &lt;code&gt;PyWaffle&lt;/code&gt; to play well with &lt;code&gt;subplots&lt;/code&gt; and 10 or&#xA;more figures. Plus, nobody wants to see 9 figures, so 8 it is.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how&#34;&gt;How?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rdquo; section kind of gave this away, but it comes through using &lt;code&gt;subplots&lt;/code&gt;&#xA;in &lt;code&gt;PyWaffle&lt;/code&gt;, as suggested by the docs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The main issue with this was trying to use the flat version of the font for the&#xA;individual waffle titles and the 3D font for the main header. The issue is that&#xA;when installed, the font shows as two separate &amp;ldquo;faces&amp;rdquo; in Windows. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t&#xA;work out how to get &lt;code&gt;matplotlib&lt;/code&gt; to distinguish between the two, so as a&#xA;workaround I just linked directly to the fonts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Edinburgh 2017 Temperatures</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2019-10-10-edinburgh-2017-temperatures/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 23:15:26 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2019-10-10-edinburgh-2017-temperatures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A ridge plot (i.e. overlapping distributions) showing the average hourly&#xA;temperatures at a particular location in Edinburgh in 2017, for the roughly&#xA;daytime hours of 7am-7pm.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how&#34;&gt;How?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is based quite heavily on&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://seaborn.pydata.org/examples/kde_ridgeplot.html&#34;&gt;an example&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;given as part of the &lt;code&gt;seaborn&lt;/code&gt; documentation. The only real tweaks made to This&#xA;are to use the average temperature to determine the hue rather than just the row&#xA;and some neat labelling.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This site has long-term data available so ideally I&amp;rsquo;d like to create an&#xA;animation showing the changes in temperature over time, though that seems like&#xA;an optimistic goal at the moment!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NFL Injury Data</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2019-10-07-nfl-injury-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 21:47:04 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2019-10-07-nfl-injury-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update 2021-04-30: Graphs updated with 2020 data, and a nicer font (Bariol, from Atipo Foundry)&lt;/em&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Update 2020-02-16: Graphs updated with 2019 data&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The NFL puts out injury data each year, covering three areas. The cover image&#xA;for this post provides the headline stat of concussions, but information is also&#xA;provided for ACL Tears:&#xA;&#xA;  &lt;div class=&#34;img-outer&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;https://ruszkow.ski/img/graphs/nfl-injuries/acl-tears.png&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;img class=&#34;scaled-img&#34; src=&#34;https://ruszkow.ski/img/graphs/nfl-injuries/acl-tears.png&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;and MCL Tears:&#xA;&#xA;  &lt;div class=&#34;img-outer&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;https://ruszkow.ski/img/graphs/nfl-injuries/mcl-tears.png&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;img class=&#34;scaled-img&#34; src=&#34;https://ruszkow.ski/img/graphs/nfl-injuries/mcl-tears.png&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how&#34;&gt;How?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A stacked bar chart in &lt;code&gt;matplotlib&lt;/code&gt;, with a bit of post-processing to make the&#xA;graphs look nice. Honestly, the biggest hassle involved in making these graphs&#xA;was getting the data itself, as the NFL inexplicably only seems to embed the&#xA;values as images.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Astronauts</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2019-09-16-astronauts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 23:13:29 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/graphs/2019-09-16-astronauts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update 2019-10-22: PyWaffle version updated to allow use of &lt;code&gt;vertical&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A waffle chart showing the number of astronauts to have achieved distance&#xA;milestones in space.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Space is cool, humans travelling in space is extra cool and this gives an&#xA;interesting way to see that a perhaps surprisingly large number of humans have&#xA;travelled to space, though very few have actually set foot on the moon.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was somewhat difficult to find precise details about this - hence the&#xA;slightly old date associated with the values. This is my best interpretation of&#xA;what&amp;rsquo;s on Wikipedia.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
