<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nonsense on ruszkow.ski</title>
    <link>https://ruszkow.ski/tags/nonsense/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nonsense on ruszkow.ski</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ruszkow.ski/tags/nonsense/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Culture Corner: November 2025</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2025-12-01-culture-corner_november-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2025-12-01-culture-corner_november-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;music&#34;&gt;MUSIC&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Turnstile&lt;/strong&gt;: I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I can remember the last time I was at a &lt;em&gt;big gig&lt;/em&gt; where it felt like the whole room was moving but my word this was frantic. Moderately stressed for the bloke who almost immediately stacked it in the pit and bounced his head off my knee, but he seemed mostly fine. I had a big yell and a dance with my pals and it was very cathartic and joyful.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Culture Corner: October 2025</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2025-11-01-culture-corner_october-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2025-11-01-culture-corner_october-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;tv&#34;&gt;TV&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mad Men&lt;/strong&gt;: In my 30-something years on earth, smoking isn&amp;rsquo;t something I&amp;rsquo;ve ever done. Not even once. The smell of cigarettes occasionally gives me a strong hit of nostalgia (gig venues pre-smoking ban, old blokes smoking terrible roll-ups at night games at Vale Park) but never enough to make me at all interested in considering it myself. And yet somehow, watching Mad Men makes me want to smoke cigarettes and drink whiskey.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Culture Corner: September 2025</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2025-10-01-culture-corner_september-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2025-10-01-culture-corner_september-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;films&#34;&gt;FILMS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Naked Gun&lt;/strong&gt;: a slightly overwhelming film (the jokes are &lt;em&gt;relentless&lt;/em&gt;) made even stranger by watching it in the cinema at 9am on a Sunday. I love a morning film at the weekend though, and simply will not be stopped.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;music&#34;&gt;MUSIC&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;King Gizzard &amp;amp; The Lizard Wizard (again)&lt;/strong&gt;: so after I mentioned getting into King Gizzard last month, on the 10th of September they decided to make all of their albums &lt;a href=&#34;https://kinggizzard.bandcamp.com/&#34;&gt;pay-what-you-want on Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;. So I went from having five of their albums to, uh, &lt;em&gt;nineteen&lt;/em&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure they&amp;rsquo;re quite as genre-hopping as some of their fans would like to make them out to be, but there truly is a wild range of styles across their various albums - nice new discoveries for me being the synth-heavy &lt;em&gt;Butterfly 3000&lt;/em&gt;, bluesy groovy &lt;em&gt;Fishing for Fishies&lt;/em&gt; and the country-tinged &lt;em&gt;Flight b741&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Culture Corner: August 2025</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2025-09-01-culture-corner_august-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2025-09-01-culture-corner_august-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;films&#34;&gt;FILMS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Better Man&lt;/strong&gt;: Hollywood paid probably literally thousands of pounds to CGI a monkey into the classic Vale Kalamazoo home shirt, and I just think that&amp;rsquo;s neat (it&amp;rsquo;s a pretty good film too).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;music&#34;&gt;MUSIC&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;King Gizzard &amp;amp; The Lizard Wizard&lt;/strong&gt;: Not sure entirely why I chose to give King Gizzard another go - I&amp;rsquo;d listened to them briefly a while ago and didn&amp;rsquo;t really think much of it. Something clicked this time though - turns out I am actually quite partial to their proggy-garage rock. Nonagon Infinity has very quickly become one of the few albums I&amp;rsquo;ll actually run to - there&amp;rsquo;s a really nice rhythm to it. With as many albums as they have (27???) it&amp;rsquo;s going to take me a long while to dig through, but I&amp;rsquo;m enjoying what I&amp;rsquo;ve heard so far.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Culture Corner: July 2025</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2025-08-01-culture-corner_july-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2025-08-01-culture-corner_july-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;films&#34;&gt;FILMS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All Cheerleaders Die&lt;/strong&gt;: when I asked my friend Alice back in April if I could crash at hers for a night to break up the journey to Cheltenham for 2000 Trees, she &lt;em&gt;immediately&lt;/em&gt; picked the film that we would watch together. I think it says a lot about our friendship that a full &lt;em&gt;three months in advance&lt;/em&gt; she already knew what the mood of the evening should be. This was absolutely terrible; I loved it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Culture Corner: June 2025</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2025-07-01-culture-corner_june-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2025-07-01-culture-corner_june-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;tv&#34;&gt;TV&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taskmaster&lt;/strong&gt;: we were pretty late to the Taskmaster game (and only started it in 2022), ended up absolutely blasting through the first 14 seasons and getting a little tired of it (those COVID seasons really were sub-par). After a bit of a break we&amp;rsquo;re back into season 15 and I am fully a Taskmaster convert once again, I now understand the appeal of Ivo Graham and Jenny Eclair&amp;rsquo;s presence is a lovely reminder of a youth spent listening to Radio 4 comedy (I was a wild child).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Culture Corner: May 2025</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2025-06-01-culture-corner_may-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2025-06-01-culture-corner_may-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;tv&#34;&gt;TV&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Race Across The World&lt;/strong&gt;: as a fussy vegetarian eater and an anxious traveller, I am unlikely to travel especially widely in the world. Race Across The World sounds like it would be my actual nightmare to participate in, but it&amp;rsquo;s an ideal show for me to watch. There&amp;rsquo;s light drama &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; occasionally heart-warming tales &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; you get to see cool and interesting bits of the world.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Silo&lt;/strong&gt;: I read the entire Silo series a few years back, but forgot just how much I enjoyed it until we started watching the series and I was overjoyed to find things actually looking like how I&amp;rsquo;d pictured them. We&amp;rsquo;re not too far into the series yet, but it&amp;rsquo;s fun so far.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Culture Corner: April 2025</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2025-05-01-culture-corner_april-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2025-05-01-culture-corner_april-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;films&#34;&gt;FILMS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Real Pain&lt;/strong&gt;: reminded me how much I miss my Polish grandmother, one of the best people I&amp;rsquo;ve ever known.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;tv&#34;&gt;TV&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You&lt;/strong&gt;: an absolute nonsense show but always entertaining. We&amp;rsquo;re just over half way through, and there is no way I could&amp;rsquo;ve guessed the turns it would take to get here.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;music&#34;&gt;MUSIC&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lonely People With Power by Deafheaven&lt;/strong&gt;: hot damn, blastbeats are so back.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Manning Fireworks by MJ Lenderman&lt;/strong&gt;: I regret missing out on tickets for his Glasgow show, every time I listen to this album I find a new little bit to appreciate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Culture Corner: March 2025</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2025-04-01-culture-corner_march-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2025-04-01-culture-corner_march-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;tv&#34;&gt;TV&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Severance&lt;/strong&gt;: it took the renaming of a group chat and some substantial nagging from friends but yes, we are now fully invested in Severance. It&amp;rsquo;s a little too stressful to completely blast through, but we got through season one at a fair pace. Lots to think about, but mainly how much I want one of the MDR keyboards.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;books&#34;&gt;BOOKS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Last Murder At The End Of The World by Stuart Turton&lt;/strong&gt;:  listening to this, I discovered the limit I have when it comes to the &amp;ldquo;performance&amp;rdquo; element of audiobooks - it&amp;rsquo;s just a touch too theatrical for me. The book itself is OK - some good spots but also a few weird lulls.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Culture Corner: February 2025</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2025-03-01-culture-corner_february-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2025-03-01-culture-corner_february-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;tv&#34;&gt;TV&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grand Designs&lt;/strong&gt;: nothing like being ill for several days to make me yearn for Kevin nodding politely while some bloke insists they won&amp;rsquo;t compromise on their budget, timescale or scope (and then ends up doing so on all three).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fallout&lt;/strong&gt;: I tried to play Fallout 3 a long, long time ago but didn&amp;rsquo;t get far because it got too stressful fast. But now there&amp;rsquo;s a TV show with all the vibes but I can turn away if it&amp;rsquo;s too weird for me? Ideal, really.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Culture Corner: January 2025</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2025-02-01-culture-corner_january-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2025-02-01-culture-corner_january-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I realise I&amp;rsquo;ve basically not been doing anything with this website and that&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a waste. That being said, I&amp;rsquo;m not finding a huge amount of time or motivation to work on personal projects so I need to find something else to fill the space.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The slow death of Twitter dot com has left me with a relative lack of places to express my Thoughts on things I enjoy (or don&amp;rsquo;t), so I think what I might try and do is some kind of monthly dump of my thoughts on stuff. Yeah, you can get some of this from Letterboxd or StoryGraph but this might be more interim thoughts (and I get to say things about music). Okay? Okay. Let&amp;rsquo;s start.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
