<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nonsense on ruszkow.ski</title>
    <link>https://ruszkow.ski/tags/nonsense/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nonsense on ruszkow.ski</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ruszkow.ski/tags/nonsense/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Culture Corner: May 2025</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2025-06-01-culture-corner_may-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2025-06-01-culture-corner_may-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;tv&#34;&gt;TV&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Race Across The World&lt;/strong&gt;: as a fussy vegetarian eater and an anxious traveller, I am unlikely to travel especially widely in the world. Race Across The World sounds like it would be my actual nightmare to participate in, but it&amp;rsquo;s an ideal show for me to watch. There&amp;rsquo;s light drama &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; occasionally heart-warming tales &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; you get to see cool and interesting bits of the world.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Silo&lt;/strong&gt;: I read the entire Silo series a few years back, but forgot just how much I enjoyed it until we started watching the series and I was overjoyed to find things actually looking like how I&amp;rsquo;d pictured them. We&amp;rsquo;re not too far into the series yet, but it&amp;rsquo;s fun so far.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Culture Corner: April 2025</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2025-05-01-culture-corner_april-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2025-05-01-culture-corner_april-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;films&#34;&gt;FILMS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Real Pain&lt;/strong&gt;: reminded me how much I miss my Polish grandmother, one of the best people I&amp;rsquo;ve ever known.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;tv&#34;&gt;TV&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You&lt;/strong&gt;: an absolute nonsense show but always entertaining. We&amp;rsquo;re just over half way through, and there is no way I could&amp;rsquo;ve guessed the turns it would take to get here.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;music&#34;&gt;MUSIC&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lonely People With Power by Deafheaven&lt;/strong&gt;: hot damn, blastbeats are so back.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Manning Fireworks by MJ Lenderman&lt;/strong&gt;: I regret missing out on tickets for his Glasgow show, every time I listen to this album I find a new little bit to appreciate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Culture Corner: March 2025</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2025-04-01-culture-corner_march-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2025-04-01-culture-corner_march-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;tv&#34;&gt;TV&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Severance&lt;/strong&gt;: it took the renaming of a group chat and some substantial nagging from friends but yes, we are now fully invested in Severance. It&amp;rsquo;s a little too stressful to completely blast through, but we got through season one at a fair pace. Lots to think about, but mainly how much I want one of the MDR keyboards.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;books&#34;&gt;BOOKS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Last Murder At The End Of The World by Stuart Turton&lt;/strong&gt;:  listening to this, I discovered the limit I have when it comes to the &amp;ldquo;performance&amp;rdquo; element of audiobooks - it&amp;rsquo;s just a touch too theatrical for me. The book itself is OK - some good spots but also a few weird lulls.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Culture Corner: February 2025</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2025-03-01-culture-corner_february-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2025-03-01-culture-corner_february-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;tv&#34;&gt;TV&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grand Designs&lt;/strong&gt;: nothing like being ill for several days to make me yearn for Kevin nodding politely while some bloke insists they won&amp;rsquo;t compromise on their budget, timescale or scope (and then ends up doing so on all three).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fallout&lt;/strong&gt;: I tried to play Fallout 3 a long, long time ago but didn&amp;rsquo;t get far because it got too stressful fast. But now there&amp;rsquo;s a TV show with all the vibes but I can turn away if it&amp;rsquo;s too weird for me? Ideal, really.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Culture Corner: January 2025</title>
      <link>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2025-02-01-culture-corner_january-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruszkow.ski/posts/2025-02-01-culture-corner_january-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I realise I&amp;rsquo;ve basically not been doing anything with this website and that&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a waste. That being said, I&amp;rsquo;m not finding a huge amount of time or motivation to work on personal projects so I need to find something else to fill the space.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The slow death of Twitter dot com has left me with a relative lack of places to express my Thoughts on things I enjoy (or don&amp;rsquo;t), so I think what I might try and do is some kind of monthly dump of my thoughts on stuff. Yeah, you can get some of this from Letterboxd or StoryGraph but this might be more interim thoughts (and I get to say things about music). Okay? Okay. Let&amp;rsquo;s start.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
